# Shivesh Gupta (guptashiv84@gmail.com)

Experienced in Front end development and Skilled in React, Tailwind, CSS, JavaScript, React Native, MERN stack, PHP .Strong logical and design professional with a Bachelor of Engineering - BE focused in Computer Science from Chitkara University.

Pno: 8968330448

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/shivesh-gupta-86712b178/

Behance: https://www.behance.net/techvectorgupta Portfolio: https://shivesh.shivesh171766cse.now.sh/

Git: https://github.com/shivesh947

#### **EDUCATION:**

Qualification/Degree	School/College	Score	Year
B. E. (CSE)	Chitkara Institute Of Engg. & Tech., Punjab	86.74% (9.13 CGPA)	2017-2021
Class XII	DAV Senior Secondary School, panchkula, Chandigarh	71.8%	2016-2017
Class X	P.N Saigal Inter college, Sitapur Lucknow(UP)	80%	2014-2015

#### WORK EXPERIENCE & PROJECTS:

- BITBNS (Buyhatke) Frontend Developer (06/2020-currently)
- 1. Creating a promotion campaign.
- 2. Generalize code for all cryptocurrency investment on bitdroplet.
- 3. Introducing ETH Coin in Bitdroplet.
- 4. Revamp Bitbns and bitdroplet Website.
- 5. Integrate Paxful Gateway in bitdroplet.
- 6. Integrate Okex Gateway in bitbns.
- 7. Add SignIn with bitbns Feature.
- 8. Add Price Prediction Platform.
- 9. Add Gift Voucher Feature
- Internship: Job Vacancy Result User Interface Designer (04/2020-06/2020)
- 1. Fixing Lot's of major designing issues.
- 2. Developing test, White collar job platform.
- 3. Fix some major front end and back-end issues also deploying skill hives website.
- 4. Working with the marketing team and back-end team helping for integration.
- Internship: The Sparks Foundation (02/2019-04/2019)

Working as a PHP developer during the session (Feb 2019-Apr 2019) of Graduate Rotational Internship Program at The Sparks Foundation on 25-Apr-2019

- Internship: Vskills India's Largest Certification Body (05/2019-07/2019)
  Internship in the area of Analysis and Development of Content for web Development (AngularJS) Domain.
- **Project**: Online MCQ Platform (September 2019 October2019)

  A MCQ platform (https://github.com/shivesh947/MOMCQT) created using *PHP and MYSQL* where multiple choice questions can be practiced by students or added by instructors.
- Project: ComponentStyler (December 2018 January 2019)
   ComponentStyler (https://github.com/shivesh947/css\_styler) is a web Application those are designed by using vanilla javascript in this application developer easily design her component in different-different state and download code as well.
   Live link(https://shivesh947.github.io/css\_styler/button%20maker%20done/temp.html)

- Project: Tourism website(Dec 2019 Jan 2020)
   Tourism website is developed by using React js, Node js, Bootstrap, Mongodb, It is a website for the tourist department and the viewer. Tourist department add information using the admin portal and client/ user checks that information easily.
- Project: Ticket\_generater using QR code (Feb 2019)
   Ticket\_generater is (https://github.com/shivesh947/Ticket\_generater\_QR) developed by using PHP,
   AJAX, MYSQL, JAVASCRIPT. In this application, clients book bus tickets. And get QR code

### **ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS:**

- Top nine teams in IEEE hackathon competition in October 2019
- ReactJS- Complete Guide for Frontend web development Live Link
- UX Design Fundamentals Coursera <u>Live Link</u>
- Tagore House Representative in secondary school.

### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS:

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP.

Database: MySQL.

**Frameworks**: Material UI, Bootstrap, Chakra UI, Tailwind, React Native,

NodeJs, ExpressJs, Laravel.

**Libraries**: React Js , Redux, UniStore, Jquery, Framer motion.

Toolkit: GulpJs, SASS, Sublime Text, VSCode.

Additional Skills: UIUX, Figma, photoshop, Github, Webpack, NPM, Window, Mac.

### **CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES:**

- Participated in a Research Induced Training in Chitkara University event in November 2018.
- Participated in a IEEE hackathon competition in October 2019.
- Participated in a Poster making competition in 2018.
- Attended workshop on NodeJs at Chitkara University in 2018.

# (Shivesh Gupta)